そんな… あの体で　一体どこへ!?
The ability to build up a shroud of Nen aura. You can make your body harder,
and considerably slow the effects of aging.
シュート！
Zetsu. A technique that nullifies your Nen aura.
なっ…！
Gon, we need to learn more about Nen.
考えてみりゃ　簡単なこと。
After two months, during which Gon
was forbidden to practice Nen, Wing has summoned Gon
and Killua to see him.
お前のさなぎは　後出しだった。
Gon-kun. Killua-kun.
こっちの意図を 知った上での待機なら それがお前の能力。
Starting today, you'll train with Zushi.
トラップってことさ。
Gon-kun, I'm pleased
ダメ押しは　俺がキセルを構えて 気を入れた瞬間の反応のなさ。
that you kept your word. It's thanks to your promise thread.
あり得ねえのよ。
A few times, I almost gave in.
反応すまいとする気配さえ ないなんてな。
But when I looked at the thread, I was able to control myself.
ク…　フフフ…。
That's because I added some Nen to help you. Huh? Really?
ん？
No, I was lying.
１５分。
Huh? But how could you tell that he kept his word?
あなたが 煙の結界の解除を決断し
He could have been practicing in secret.
実行するまでに 消費すると踏んだ時間。
Because the promise thread remained intact.
その間 私は　そっと煙をすり抜け 自由に動き回る予定でした。
Gon-kun, it's been a while,
but would you try using Ten ? It's okay? Yes.
私を結界に閉じ込めたのは 王との分断のためでしょう？
Crap, do I remember how to do this?
つまり　煙の牢獄がある限り それを見て　あなたの仲間は
It's been so long. Can I still pull it off?
あなたの仲間を 静かに始末して行く。
Zushi, what do you think?
実行するのに じゅうぶんの時間
I-It's amazing!
あなたは迷っているだろうと。
His aura is flowing all around him!
１５分もの間　抜け殻を前にか？
Soft and calm...
随分と見くびられたもんだな。
But it's very strong!
いいえ 私は買いかぶっていたのです。
I did it! Whew... I was worried that I might
have forgotten how.
あなたを！
Once you've learned the technique,
you can't forget it. However, to become a master, you'll have to train hard.
これで　「スモーキージェイル」を すり抜けたとしたら
But it felt easier than before, despite not having been practicing Ten. That's because
ひと粒ひと粒は 目に見えねえわけだ
you were training your spirit each day. Now, look at your left hand.
あっ！
Huh?
なぜなら このすり抜けは　苦肉の策。
if you broke your promise and used Nen, it would snap. That's actually possible?
正直　私は困っていたのですよ。
Hey, Wing-san...
閉じ込められている状況に。
Did you watch Kastro and Hisoka's match? Yes, I did.
下手な陽動だな　矛盾してるぜ。
What was the ability that Hisoka used?
お前は　ちゃんと すり抜けただろうが！
Could we send loose limbs flying around? Hmm, that's a difficult question.
あの時点ではね。
Gon-kun, have you seen the fight on video? No, not yet.
私は　あなたが　もっと 優秀な兵士だと思っていました。 初志を貫徹　任務に忠実。
Then I'll explain while we watch.
ホントに　ありがとう。
Can you see the threads of aura
extending from his left hand?
ありがとう　ありがとう…。
Threads of aura? Yes.
アハハハ…！
It's a high-level application of Zetsu, known as In.
破壊できねえ！ 分裂し　また集まるだけ
When you use In, even the strongest opponents will
find it hard to see your aura.
無敵？
The most effective counter to this technique
アハハハ…！ サンキュー　バイバイ！
is to focus the aura created by Ren into your eyes, a technique called Gyo.
だまされるな これは奴の心理作戦
The method Gon-kun used
in his fight with Gido
あの時点での　さなぎへの攻撃は ベストの選択
might work, as well.
いや　終わったことを 考えてる時点で奴の術中
However, you couldn't take offensive action, so ultimately, you'd throw your life away.
次にやるべきことは
Right.
分散した奴の目的を予想し 阻止する
My assignment for you two
他の護衛団との接触
is to practice Ren until you
can see through Hisoka's In. Eh?
俺以外の敵を発見　せん滅
Uh, master?
そして　王との再会
What should I do?
間違いねえ！ 全て俺の利害と一致する！
Zushi, you should already be strong
enough to see past his In.
問題ねえ！
I should?
あっ！
Show them your Ren.
うわっ…　うわっ！
O-Osu!
こいつは　大事に捨てておくよ！
Ren!
アハハハ…！
It's so strong.
やられた もう　新たに技は出せねえ
It doesn't have a much greater magnitude, but it's very dense.
「ディープパープル」を 解除したら俺は丸腰 もう　「ディープパープル」だけで しのぎ切るしかねえ
Then direct that aura into your eyes. Osu!
エスパーは。
Gyo!
うっ…。
So, can you see the aura that emanates
んっ？
from Hisoka's body?
あっ？
And how many threads are there?
今の体調で出せたマックス
No, I think it's thirteen.
これで　ナックルを 全力でサポートする！
Not quite. But you were close.
狙いは　分かった
You're making excellent progress, Zushi. O-Osu...
１発は　くれてやる 代わりに…
Thank you very much. By channeling all your power through Gyo, you achieved a level where you
could see through Hisoka's In.
命をもらう！
But with enough training, you'll be able to use Gyo while fighting.
オッケー　誰もいないよ。
First, practice Ren, and master the Ren application known as Gyo.
今なら逃げられる　行こ行こ！
Then you'll discover the true nature
…ったく　ここなら 絶対安全って言ってたのに
of Hisoka's ability.
レオル様　全然 連絡取れなくなっちゃうしさ。
And will you be able to use that same ability?
お腹 引っ込んじゃったってことは
My answer is both yes and no.
ヂートゥ様も やられちゃったんだろうな。 フラッタも全然　音沙汰なしだし もう　いいよね。
Regardless of what Hisoka's precise power is, so long as it uses Nen, you can learn it.
私も女王　目指して 旅しちゃおうっと！
However, Nen powers depend on the
particular individual.
その時は　あんた 副女王にしたげる！　いいでしょ？
Each of us possesses different
specialties and preferences.
助…　けて…。 あっ？
Thus, Nen differs for each person.
頼む　出して…くれ…。 助けて…。
If you're serious about mastering Nen, you shouldn't merely copy others' abilities.
や　ビゼフ長官　大変。
It's important that you first identify
your own strengths.
足が…　動かんのだ。
Strengths...
うん？　うん…。
You've only just begun to develop. You haven't settled on one form yet.
いよ　行こ　危ないし。
Initially, try to grow as much as you can.
なっ…　待ってくれ！　頼む！
That is the purpose of this training.
このままじゃ死んでしまう。 無理よ そんなもの動かせないもん。
Train hard, play hard, and enjoy life.
じゃあ　せめて 誰か呼んで来てくれ！
Osu!
だから！ こっちは　一刻も早く こんなとこ逃げたいの！
The final day of Killua-kun's
window to fight is June 9th, and Gon-kun's is the 10th, correct?
ボスが消息不明で 王とは直接のつながりないし 宮殿は　めちゃくちゃ！
I'd like you both to register for your final day.
ここにいる意味 もう　全くないんだけど！
In the meantime, you'll train.
褒美なら　いくらでも出す！
You must learn Gyo
before it's time for your battle.
地下に 財宝が　うなるほどあるんだ！
Osu!
助けてくれたら 望むもの何でもやる！
Your Ren was impressive, Zushi.
だから頼む！　早く　ここから…。
You moved way ahead while I was resting.
地下のどこ？ シェルターのずっと先に 総帥専用のエリアがあって
No, I still have a long path before me.
そこの財宝を 私が管理してるんだ！
Hey, let's practice what we just learned.
自由に出入りできるのは私だけ… うっ…。
Yeah, then let's go to your room, Gon. Okay.
おりゃあ！
Killua... Zushi.
お。
We have company.
お宝　お宝　お宝 限界だ
You guys don't know when to quit.
この国は終わり
That's why no one likes you.
私への根回しなしに
Oh, don't be so harsh.
空爆が始まったのが　いい証拠
Tell me when you're going to fight, because I'd love to be your opponent.
恐らく　アリが生物兵器という 絶好の口実になったんだ
I guess they specialize in hunting newbies.
連合側に私が捕まれば
They want to rack up wins
by beating us up.
つじつま合わせの自供を 強要され
We're getting desperate...
一生拘束か　口封じの死
Because our deadline is nearing. Come on, let's fight.
うっ…。 捕まってたまるか！
I'll even demonstrate my power
絶対　逃げ切ってやる！
right now.
これで　煙使いは脱落
Hey, Gon! That won't work.
あとは宮殿に戻り 現状を把握し　王の元へ
My deadline is May 29th. Fight on that day.
恐らく　私がおそばに付いても
Who cares about your deadline, moron?
王は うるさがられるだけでしょうが
Let's go. Gon-chan...
さぁ　わが一部達。
I guarantee it.
宮殿にいる者の位置 状態を知るのです。
Gon, ignore him.
アハハハ！
What will you do?
プフの「ベルゼブブ」は 自分の体を最小ナノサイズまで
I'll force him to fight me.
自身を　さまざまな大きさ 数に分割することが可能で
Visualize the energy building in your body.
サイズが小さければ小さいほど その数は増える ただし　司令塔となる本体は
Power gathers in each cell, and grows.
最小でもハチ程度の大きさを 維持しなければならない
Then you force that power out!
私自身は脱出できませんでした
I'm getting used to this.
それは　私の戦闘力の 半減を意味します
Learning when to shroud the
boosted aura with Ten was a little tricky.
比べるべくもないことは
They pick it up too fast!
分身を扱う　あなたならば よく　お分かりでしょう
But our auras still aren't as strong as Zushi's.
本体が解かれた私に 死角なし！
Guess we should practice more. N-No, that's enough!
あなたの負けです
Learning when to rest is part of training.
あなたは　もっと 慎重に迷うべきだったのです
Let's call it a day. Really? I can still—
そうすれば少なくとも
No!
さなぎが もぬけだと気付いた後も 消えた中身が結界の外に 出たのかどうかで　迷えたはず
If they pass me in half a day,
I'll lose all my motivation... Oh... Well, it's okay.
さらに　私が結界の外から 声を掛けたとしても
We'll practice more tomorrow. Yeah.
それが本物かどうかで 迷えたのです
See you tomorrow.
先ほど あなたに吐露した作戦は
Bye.
私にとって　いわば決死の策 いくら　私が外で あなたの仲間をかく乱しようと
Okay, then...
苦もなく 私自身を捜し出したでしょう
I can't...
そうなれば　この姿の私には
I can't move!
あなたに　あらがうすべは もう　なかった
I can't talk or breathe...
要するに
What's going on?
仲間の痛みを伴うものの
Oops.
そして私は　１０％ほどは それを覚悟していた
Please...
直前の大爆発で 心が　ぶれたのでしょう 残念です
Forget it.
しかし　おかげで私は自由！
I figured you were up to something.
次は 宮殿の状況を掌握します！
But you don't need dirty tricks
to make me fight you.
突入前の段階で
When do you want to fight?
既に　モラウが万全の体調からは
Don't worry. I'll let you win.
遠い状態にあったのは 間違いない
I'll even give you each a win.
そのモラウが 極度の緊張状態の中
Is that good enough?
プフとの神経戦に臨み 疲労と焦燥から 早まった判断に 身を委ねたのも確かである
After I get my win off you, I'm going to fight Gon-chan.
しかし　ユピーとナックルの 一騎打ちを防ぎ
If you want to fight Gon, you'll have to follow his schedule.
サポートできたのは あの場面以外にはなかった
He'll be more than happy to fight you. I can promise you that.
結果的には　「スモーキージェイル」を解く タイミングとして
Okay.
唯一無二 絶妙の判断だったといえる それは　偶然の産物によってのみ 生じたのでなく
If you two are willing to fight, we don't need to bother with this. Let's go register together.
モラウの　あまたの経験にも 助けられたと解釈するのが
Once that's done, I'll return the boy unharmed.
妥当である
Yeah, yeah. Sure...
モラウは　突入直後 実際に目の当たりにした 敵の戦力と
But only this once.
仲間の戦力とをはかりに掛け 当初の読みが甘過ぎたことを
May 29th...
無意識下では感じていたのだ
Okay, happy now?
仲間が　ギリギリ 持ちこたえられる時間が
Yes, we'll return him.
そのために　自分が　「スモーキージェイル」を 解いてまで助けに行く
Oh, just to reiterate, it's a one-time deal.
是非との葛藤からよけるため
If you break your promise...
理屈を　さなぎへの攻撃に 転嫁したにすぎない
Eh... Whatever.
モラウの老獪な 戦場での処世術が
Forget it. What? You got me curious.
仲間の窮地を救ったのだ
What will happen if we break our promise? No point in telling you now.
分身に紛れて 本物が俺を攻撃する作戦だろ？
Just keep your word.
カウンターをくれてやるぜ 今度こそ！
Hello? Is this Gon-kun?
５体　消された あと８４体！
I'm sure you'll understand what this means.
フフフ…　やはり　しょせん 煙は　まがいもの 感触が違う 本物の拳は 俺に触れれば確実に分かる
As long as you don't tell anyone,
and you follow my instructions, the three of you will be able to
train as usual tomorrow.
その時が貴様の最期だ！
Zushi...
あと７５…　７２… あと７０！
How did it go with Gon-chan? Perfect.
すぐそばに 敵とおぼしき少年１名。
Not killing people is pretty hard.
地下シェルター入り口付近に３名。 ヒナと兵隊アリ１匹 そしてビゼフ。
Clean living's tough...
前の３名を尾行しているもよう。
Come on down! We have tickets!
あの娘は　龍の矢に やられたらしいですね
These are fresh off the press...
しかし　なぜ　そばの敵は ピトーを攻めない？
Gon versus Sadaso! And here's Killua versus Sadaso...
娘の知り合いか？
If you don't buy now, you'll regret it!
数日前に捕らえた人間。
Pops. Yep? Does Sadaso have only one arm?
もうすぐ生まれるもよう。 うおっ！　ここは　すげぇ！
Yeah, the one-armed fighter,
with the mask-like face.
敵が　いっぱいだ！ ひ　ふ　み…
If he catches you with his
invisible left arm, you're finished.
あっ　でも ユピーがどんどん消してる
They call him the newbie crusher...
宮殿北西部に ユピーと敵　約５０名。
That bastard.
煙のおっさんと たくさんのヤンキー達。
Huh? Killua?
あと　変なトンガリ頭のデブ。
Gon, you were here?
敵味方不明。
Y-Yeah...
トンガリ頭は ユピーの新能力？
Killua-kun, I believe you helped Zushi last night. Thank you.
ヤンキーは１人だけ本物で
You feeling all right?
他は煙の分身でしょう
Yeah, I'm fine.
消えた分身が増えないのは
I was probably tired.
やはり キセルが能力の要だったから
Sorry to worry you! Oh, Wing-san...
ユピーなら１分とかけずに 本物にたどり着くでしょう
Can we watch that video again? I've learned how to use Gyo.
はっ！ 王がいない！　一体どこへ!? 皆さん いったん戻って来るのです！
Really?
フフフ…　どうした？
Fifteen threads, right?
どんどん分身が減って行くぞ 俺の攻撃が速過ぎて 懐に入ることすら かなわぬと見える
Thirteen for the cards, one for the scarf, and a well hidden one that
leads to the arm he tossed.
つくってやるか　わざと隙を
Continue. Hisoka is...
奴が俺に 打ち込みやすいように
Hisoka's aura appears
慎重に…
to expand and contract.
自然に…
Or does it attract certain objects, similar to a magnet?
さぁ　ここだ！
Why else would his arm reattach?
来い！
Or fly into his opponent's chin?
こいつも!?
He's on a completely different level! Very good... You pass.
てめぇ！
But I am surprised...
本物なんざ 初めっからいねえんだよ。
Gon? Uh-huh, but I still couldn't figure out Hisoka's power.
ぶっ殺す!!
So, Killua-kun, since you finished your assignment,
I assume you want to fight, yes?
当たりめぇだろ!!
I just got an itch to fight.
あっ！ オーラの爆発？　ユピーの？
Actually, I've already chosen my day to fight. May 29th.
あの状況で 使うほどの技ですか？
Mine's May 30th. That's fine.
気にはなりますが
Spend the remaining days practicing Ten and Ren.
優先すべきは 王の行方を知ること！
Be sure you get plenty
of practice, rest, and sleep.
助かったぜ　ボス
Osu!
あの条件付けがなかったら キレて突っ込むとこだった
Killua... They must have threatened you.
) ((俺がお前の怒った顔の 分身を出すのは
Yeah, but my biggest concern
お前が　ぶちキレて周りが 全く見えてない時だけだからな)) ((それを見たら お前はいったん分身に混じって
was the master, and he agreed. But I'm worried they'll use Zushi again. It'll be okay.
現状でやるべきことを ちゃんと考えろ))
You don't need to worry.
((へいへいへい 分かりやしたって))
Today, I'll beat Killua-chan for my sixth win.
あいつが　シュートを 連れ去れるわけがねえんだった
Tomorrow, I'll beat Gon-chan
for my seventh win.
かといって　もう自力では 動けないシュートを一体誰が？
Then I just need to find three more chumps.
クソっ！　考えるな！
And I'll be a Floor Master.
集中力　欠いて 手に負える相手かよ！
I'll get all the wealth and glory to
set me up for the rest of my life.
ここは…
Move, and I will kill you... Use Nen, and I will kill you.
どこだ？
Make a sound, and I will kill you.
あれは…
Do you know what happens
if you break your word?
ひ！ ヤバい！ 急いで早く！ ふさがっちゃう前に入るよ！
Never show your filthy face to us again.
クソっ！ ビゼフは俺の獲物だぞ！
That's a promise.
奴らの能力さえ分かれば 手が打てるんだが…
Time has run out for Sadaso!
はっ！ それ以上…　こっちへ来るな。
Thanks to their inborn talent, Gon and Killua are learning Nen
at incredible speeds. Now they will start the real battle
プフ！
at Heavens Arena.